# **Amal Joy Chemparathy**

Berlin, Germany amaljoyc@gmail.com



## LINKS

#### GitHub

https://github.com/amaljoyc

#### LinkedIn

https://de.linkedin.com/in/amaljoyc

#### **Personal Blog**

https://amaljoyc.github.io/

## **SKILLS**

## **Expert**

Java

**Spring Core** 

Spring Cloud

Maven

Microservices

PostgreSQL

Linux / Bash

#### **Prior Experience**

Python

Django

Groovy

Jenkins

Docker

Chef

NodeJS

Kafka

## Languages

English (Expert)

German (Basic)

Malayalam (Native)

# **SUMMARY**

I'm a Software Engineer with 7+ years of professional experience in the design, architecture and development of many Software Applications. I have a strong passion for solving problems and building products and solutions through the application of technology.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

# 2018 - present TECHNICAL PRODUCT OWNER - smava GmbH

- ✓ I'm currently refactoring smava's Legacy Monolithic applications into Scalable Microservices using Spring Boot and Spring Cloud.
- ✓ As a Tech Lead, my responsibilities are to make tech decisions, design and architect various software components and support its development, manage both project and delivery, and hire new Engineers.
- ✓ Reporting to Engineering VP
- ✓ Tech Stack includes Java 8, Spring Boot, Maven, Microservices, PostgreSQL, Redis etc.

#### 2016 - 2018 SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - smaya GmbH

- ✓ Developed the backend logic for smava.de and various other internal projects using Java/Spring/Maven for development and PostgreSQL for data persistence.
- ✓ Developed many Product Solutions for Marketing, CRM, Customer Facing App etc.
- ✓ Worked on very complex and legacy monolithic applications as well as some new micro-services.
- ✓ Hands-on experience building APIs for the frontend, integrating third-party APIs, building Backend For Frontend, Security Management in web apps etc.
- ✓ Did some scripting using Bash, Python, Groovy, Golang, and Jenkins for automated deployment and testing.
- ✓ Used Java, Spring, Maven, DataNucleus, Hibernate, PostgreSQL, Git, Linux, Bash, Jenkins, NodeJS, Kafka etc

# 2015 - 2016 IT CONTRACTOR - Deutsche Telekom AG

- ✓ Lead the development / support of a 4 year old telecom project named HCS-RCS (configuring handsets to use Message+ Application).
- ✓ Worked closely with Product Owner following Agile / Scrum based development.
- ✓ Main support/contact for the Development, QA and Operations team.
- ✓ Used Technologies and Tools like Java 7, Groovy, Spring, Maven, Git, LDAP, Chef, Docker, PostgreSQL, Linux.

# 2013 – 2015 SYSTEMS ENGINEER – Infosys Ltd.

- ✓ Provided Software Services by performing end to end development like analysis, design and implementation of user stories including unit and integration testing.
- ✓ Implemented SOAP and REST interfaces. Used LDAP and PostgreSQL for data storage. Other tools used were Java 6, Spring, Maven, Git, Linux, Chef.
- ✓ All projects using Agile (Scrum) software development methodology.

## 2012 - 2013 INTERN PROGRAMMER - Aplopio Technology

- ✓ Involved in the development of the recruiting software Recruiterbox (recruiterbox.com).
- ✓ Worked on server-side / backend web development using Python and Django with PostgreSQL and MongoDB for data persistence.

# 2010 - 2012 WEB ADMINISTRATOR / STUDENT INTERN - Toc H Institute of Science & Technology

✓ Maintained (minor development and bug fix) an internal college departmental website.

## **EDUCATION**

2008 – 2012 Bachelor of Technology
Computer Science & Engineering
Cochin University

# **CERTIFICATIONS / TRAININGS**

2015	Oracle Certified Professional
	Java SE 6 Programmer
2013	Programming Languages

Coursera Course Certificate